Instantiate is a function to create
Instantiate はゲームオブジェクトのクローンを作成する
clones of game objects. This is commonly
関数です。これは
used in the context of cloning a prefab.
プレハブのクローンを使用する場面で主に使用されます。
A prefab is simply a preconfigured
プレハブとは、単に事前設定された
object saved in the project's assets.
オブジェクトであり、プロジェクトの Assets に保存されます。
One such example might be firing rockets
ひとつの例はバズーカからロケットを発射するケースです。
from a bazooka. Each of the rockets
各々のロケットは
would need to be instantiated in to the
ゲーム空間にインスタンス化して
game world so that it could be fired.
発射できるようにします。
In this example we're using 'Fire1' to trigger
このサンプルでは  'Fire1' を使用して Instantiate 関数を
an instantiate function. The most basic
トリガーします。もっとも基本的な
form of instantiate simply takes one parameter,
Instantiate の使用方法では引数はひとつのみであり、
the object that we wish to clone.
クローンしたオブジェクトを指定します。
In this example we have created a public
このサンプルでは、 rocketPrefab と呼ばれる
variable called rocketPrefab and we're
public 変数を作成して、
passing this in to the instantiate command.
これを Instantiate コマンドに渡します。
However this means that the prefab will be
しかし、この場合はプレハブは
instantiated at it's default position,
デフォルトの位置である原点に
which is 0. And in our example that position
インスタンス化されます。このサンプルでは、その位置は
is the centre of the world, and the centre
ワールド空間の中心であり、
of where the bazooka is at the moment.
バズーカが現在ある中心の位置です。
So when we press play
このためゲーム再生すると
those rockets appear at the centre
ロケットはバズーカの中心に
of the bazooka.
表示されます。
Instead we want to fire it like a rocket,
その代わりにロケットのように発射したいため、
so it needs to appear to be coming from
バズーカの銃身から出てくるように
the barrel of our bazooka.
表示される必要があります。
For this we need a slightly different version
このためには、Instantiate のわずかに異なった
of instantiate. This version of instantiate
バージョンが必要です。この Instantiate のバージョンでは
takes three parameters,
3 つの変数が必要です。
the object to be instantiated, in our case
インスタンス化されるオブジェクト、すなわち今回はロケットと、
the rocket prefab, and then a position
プレハブの新しいクローンを作成するための Position および
and rotation to give our new clone of the prefab.
Rotation です。
For this I've created an empty gameobject
あらかじめ空のゲームオブジェクトを作成して
that's been positioned in front of the
バズーカの銃身の前に
bazookas barrel. We are using this by
配置しています。BarrelEnd と呼ばれる
creating a public variable called BarrelEnd
public 変数を作成して、さらに
and we use this component's position and rotation
このコンポーネントの Position および Rotation の値を使用して
values as those for the new clone of our
新しいロケット プレハブの新しいクローンが出来ます。
rocket prefab. So by dragging and dropping this
これを新しい場所に
new empty location to my script in the
インスペクタ上の空の場所に
inspector I can
ドラッグ＆ドロップすることで
receive the transform position and rotation
Transform の Position および Rotation について
by making use of the barrel end variable.
BarrelEnd 変数を使用できます。
So when I press play and press fire
このためゲーム再生して、 Fire を押すと
the rocket appears in the right place
ロケットは正しい場所に登場します。
but it just kind of drops,
しかし、現時点ではただ落下して、
which is not what we want.
期待している動きではありません。
We need to be able to effect the object
インスタンス化により作成したオブジェクト
that's created by our instantiation,
を変更できることが必要です。
i.e., the clone of the rocket,
すなわち、ロケットのクローンであり、
as standard instantiate returns a type
通常の Instantiate は Object と呼ばれる型を
called Object. But in order to fire our rocket
戻します。しかしロケットを発射するためには
we're going to change that type to a rigidbody.
型を Rigidbody に変更します。
To do this we use as RigidBody
これを実現するためには Instantiate コールの後に
after the instantiate call and store the
RigidBody を使用して戻り値を
the returned value in a rigidbody variable,
rigidbody 変数に格納し、
which we'll call rocketInstance.
rocketInstance と呼ぶことにします。
So here we setup a rigidbody variable
ここで rocketInstance と呼ばれる
called rocketInstance, and we set that
Ridibody 変数をセットアップして
variable equal to our instantiate
変数を Instantiate 関数の戻り値と
function's return. Then given that this is
等しくします。これにより
now a rigidbody we can use our variable
これは Rigidbody であり rocket インスタンスの変数を使用して
rocket instance and address anything within
Rigidbody クラスの中にある全て、
the rigidbody class, for example addForce.
例えば addForce を見つけることが出来ます。
And again we can make use of the transform
そして再び barrelEnd の Transform を使用して
barrelEnd to grab the direction
Force を追加した方向を
at which we want to add a force.
取得することが出来ます。
And we can multiply by a certain amount.
さらにこれに特定の量を掛け算することが出来ます。
So now when I press play
これでゲーム再生をして、
and fire, my rockets are fired off
発射したとき、作成したクローンに
in to the distance by adding a force to
Force を加えることによって
the clone that I create.
ロケットは遠くへ発射されます。
Bare in mind that when you create many clones
多くのクローンをゲームの中で作成したとき
within the game those things will still
それらはシーンの中に
exist within your scene. So if doing
残ります。もし
something like this you may want to consider
このようなことをする場合、
writing a script which removes them from
一定時間の後にワールド空間から破棄するスクリプトが
the world after a certain amount of time.
必要な場合があります。
Here my prefab has a rocket destruction script
ここではプレハブは RocketDestruction スクリプトがあり、
which simply removes the object
1.5 秒後に
after 1 and a half seconds.
オブジェクトを破棄します。 (翻訳:gamesonytablet)